# BRYNLEY McDonald

## **CONTACT DETAILS**

Carlaw Park Student Residence 19 Nicholls Lane Auckland Central, Auckland 1010 New Zealand

Mob: +64 22 414 6893

Website: <a href="http://zephire.nz">http://zephire.nz</a>

Github: <a href="http://github.com/ZephireNZ">http://github.com/ZephireNZ</a> Email: brynleymcdonald@gmail.com

## PERSONAL STATEMENT

I am currently studying a Bachelor of Science in Computer Science, with the goals to enter the programming industry full time with past experience, a tertiary degree, and a true passion for the job I do.

I've been employed by businesses for development of websites and software giving me hands on experience in programming. In addition, working in a retail situation has given me a deeper understanding of the customer, and the ability to work within a team to meet goals and deadlines.

## **SKILLS AND ABILITIES**

### **Technical Experience**

- In-production development experience designing, coding, and maintaining
   Java applications
- Over 2 years of study in Computer Science
- Self-motivated to learn new things, through personal research or guided learning

## Ability to work well in a team

- Experience in a retail store, working as part of a team to meet the customer's needs, as well as those of the business.
- 2 years working behind-the-scenes for school productions, with critical team roles.

#### Customer relations

- Ability to express more complex ideas simply with customer
- Professional handling of various situations, including frustrated or angered customers
- Finding the right solution

## **WORK HISTORY**

#### **Dick Smith Electronics**

Part-time from 2014 – Present

Casual from 2012 - Present

Sales Consultant / Sales Manager

- Providing the customer with a complete solution for their needs.
- Keeping current with technology trends.
- Balancing customer needs and business interests.

**Noirland**Development of 'plugin' software for a Minecraft server

- Planning of software outlined by client.
- Creating that software to meet brief and specifications.
- Implementing and updating software.

Studio 128 Casual from 2011 – 2013

Web Design and Systems Upkeep

- Development and design of business website.
- Meeting with client to reach an outcome.
- Upkeep of designed systems.

#### **AWARDS**

## **Grant Shayler Award**

2013

"Awarded in memory of Grant Shayler, a former student, an outstanding software developer and engineer, whose expertise was legendary. Given each year to a student who, like Grant, has studied IT and who has the intention of continuing their studies at the tertiary level."

#### **Russell Free Memorial Award**

2013

"Awarded to the student(s) who have made a lasting impact on Newlands

College by selflessly devoting much of their time to the arts."

## **EDUCATION**

## University of Auckland – BSc CompSci/LogiComp

2014 - Present

- A in COMPSCI314 Modern Data Communications
- A- in COMPSCI340 Operating Systems
- A- in COMPSCI107 Computer Science Fundamentals
- A- in COMPSCI210 Computer Systems
- A- in COMPSCI230 Software Construction
- B+ in MKTG151G Essential Marketing

#### REFERENCES

Available on Request

Curriculum Vitae – Brynley McDonald brynleymcdonald@gmail.com